YI ZENG

(858)-952-2135 ♦ y4zeng@eng.ucsd.edu Google Scholar ♦ Github ♦ LinkedIn Personal Webpage

SUMMARY

Currently pursuing a master's degree in machine learning and data science under the ECE department at the University of California, San Diego. Expected graduating around January 2021. I value myself as a self-motivated and innovative young researcher with great interest and outstanding experience in **Security-concerned & Trustworthy Deep Learning** algorithms.

Beforehand, with the help of Deep Learning, scenarios including **Network Traffic Classification and Intrusion Detection**, **Mobile Ad-hoc Network Security**, were studied. I am currently researching on acquiring sound inference results for Deep Learning models against **Adversarial Learning** and **Backdoor Learning**.

EDUCATION

University of California, San Diego, CA, USA
Master Degree on Machine Learning and Data Science
Xidian University, Xi'an, Shaanxi, China
Bachelor Degree on Electrical and Information Engineering

Aug. 2019 - Present GPA: **3.80/4.00** Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2019

GPA: **3.71/4.00**

SELECTED COURSEWORK

Deep Learning & Applications, Optimization & Acceleration of Deep Learning on Various Hardware Platforms, Statistical Learning, Probability & Statistics for Data Science, Random Processes, Programming for Data Analysis

SELECTED PROJECTS

Project ① (2020): Mitigating White-box Adversarial Attacks toward Deep Learning Models with Preprocessing-only Techniques as the Defense.

Advisor: Dr. Han Qiu & Prof. Meikang Qiu

- Designed the first preprocessing-only adversarial defense method that demonstrates robustness against advanced interactive adversarial attacks (BPDA and EOT) on an Inception V3 model pre-trained on ImageNet.
- Developed the first preprocessing-only adversarial defense framework for DNNs includes fifteen methods.
- Lead writing three papers summarize three different contributions of this project, sent to IEEE TDSC, AAAI 2020, and ICA3PP 2020 (accepted), respectively.

Project ② (2020): Research on Developing Preprocessing-based Techniques to Mitigate Backdoor Attacks in DNNs.

Advisor: Dr. Han Qiu & Prof. Tianwei Zhang

- Surveyed and evaluated 64 existing preprocessing methods on mitigating six different advanced backdoor attacks over three different target models trained on three different datasets.
- Proposed the GYM, a comprehensive backdoor defense method, which is the first defense that considers invisible backdoor attacks and successfully mitigates different advanced attacks in attack agnostic settings.

Project (3) (2019): Designing of Light-weight Network Traffic Classification/Identification Methods only Requires Raw Packets Based on Deep Learning Techniques.

Advisor: Prof. Huaxi Gu

- Developed an Encrypted Traffic Classification (ETC) and Intrusion Detection (ID) method based on CNN, LSTM, and SAE, outperforming published methods by 13.49 % on ETC's F1 and 12.15% on ID's F1.
- Proposed a Spatio-Temporal network traffic examination method based on 1D-CNN and LSTM, which attained an averaging accuracy of 99.98% on 2 public datasets.
- Wrote 2 papers summarize project's 2 phases, published on IEEE Access, SmartCloud 2019, respectively.

Project 4 (2018): Research on Machine Learning Based Techniques Countering Security Issues in the Vehicle Ad-hoc Network (VANET).

Advisor: Prof. Meikang Qiu

- Designed a detection method for the VANET based on SVM, DNN, and Game Theory to overcome scenarios where most units are compromised, demonstrated a 7.23% higher accuracy than state-of-art methods
- Designed a detection method inputs raw traffic data to monitor and inspect malicious communications between vehicles based on Deep Learning, achieved 0.97 F1 out of 1.
- Lead writing two works summarize the details, published on SmartCom 2018, SmartCloud 2019.

EXPERIENCE OVERVIEW

Jacobs School of Engineering, UCSD, CA, USA

Research Assistant @ Adaptive Computing and Embedded Systems Lab

School of Info. and Comm. Engineering, BUPT, Beijing, China

Research Assistant @ BUPT ROHDE & SCHWARZ Joint Lab

College of Electrical Engineering, Columbia University, NY, USA

Research Intern @ Signal Processing & Communications Lab

College of Electrical Engineering, XDU, Shaanxi, China

Research Assistant @ State Key Lab of Integrated Service Networks

Aug. 2019 - Present

3 Publications

Jul. 2019 - Oct. 2019

3 Publications

Mar. 2018 - Mar. 2019

3 Publications

Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2019

4 Publications

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Programming: Python, Matlab, C/C++, HTML

Languages: Mandarin (Native), English (Full professional proficiency)

Frameworks: Tensorflow, Pytorch, Numpy, Cleverhans, Foolbox, SciPy, Scikit-learn

PROFESSIONAL SERVICES

Reviewer: Springer, 20th International Conference on Algorithms and Architectures for Parallel Processing

Reviewer: IEEE, 22nd International Conference on Computational Science and Engineering Reviewer: IEEE, 18th International Conference on Optical Communications and Networks Reviewer: IEEE, 17th International Conference on Embedded and Ubiquitous Computing

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS & MANUSCRIPTS

(i) GYM: A Comprehensive Defense Approach against DNN Backdoor Attacks Yi Zeng, Han Qiu, Shangwei Guo, Tianwei Zhang, Meikang Qiu and Bhavani Thuraisingham Under Reviewing by AAAI, 2020.

(ii) Defending Adversarial Examples in Computer Vision based on Data Augmentation Techniques
 Yi Zeng, Han Qiu, Gerard Memmi and Meikang Qiu
 Best Paper of the International Conference on Algorithms & Architectures for Parallel Processing (ICA3PP), 2020.

(iii) An Effective and Efficient Preprocessing-based Approach to Mitigate Advanced Adversarial Attacks Han Qiu*, Yi Zeng*, Qinkai Zheng, Tianwei Zhang, Meikang Qiu and Bhavani Thuraisingham Under Reviewing by AAAI, 2020. [*Equal Contribution].

(iv) FenceBox: A Platform for Defeating Adversarial Examples with Data Augmentation Techniques Han Qiu, Yi Zeng, Tianwei Zhang and Meikang Qiu Submitted to IEEE Transactions on Dependable and Secure Computing, 2020.

(v) The Hidden Vulnerability of Watermarking for Deep Neural Networks Shangwei Guo, Tianwei Zhang, Han Qiu, Yi Zeng, Tao Xiang and Yang Liu Under Reviewing by AAAI, 2020.

(vi) Deep Learning Based Network Encrypted Traffic Classification and Intrusion Detection Framework Yi Zeng, Huaxi Gu, Wenting Wei and Yantao Guo IEEE Access, 2019. 32 Citations.

(vii) End-to-End Network Traffic Classification System With Spatio-Temporal Features Extraction Yi Zeng, Zihao Qi, Wencheng Chen and Yanzhe Huang. IEEE International Conference on Smart Cloud (IEEE SmartCloud), IEEE, 2019.

(viii) DeepVCM: A Deep Learning Based Intrusion Detection Method in VANET Yi Zeng, Meikang Qiu, Dan Zhu, Zhihao Xue, Jian Xiong and Meiqin Liu IEEE Intl Conference on High Performance and Smart Computing (IEEE HPSC), IEEE, 2019.

(ix) Using Adversarial Examples to Bypass Deep Learning Based URL Detection System Wencheng Chen, Yi Zeng and Meikang Qiu IEEE International Conference on Smart Cloud (IEEE SmartCloud), IEEE, 2019.

(x) V-PSC: A Perturbation-Based Causative Attack Against DL Classifiers' Supply Chain in VANET Yi Zeng, Meikang Qiu, Jingqi Niu, Yanxin Long, Jian Xiong and Meiqin Liu IEEE International Conference on Embedded and Ubiquitous Computing (IEEE EUC), IEEE, 2019.

(xi) Model Uncertainty for Annotation Error Correction in DL Based Intrusion Detection System Wencheng Chen, Hongyu Li, Yi Zeng, Zichang Ren and Xingxin Zheng IEEE International Conference on Smart Cloud (IEEE SmartCloud), IEEE, 2019.

(xii) Senior2local: A Machine Learning Based Intrusion Detection Method for VANETs Yi Zeng, Meikang Qiu, Zhong Ming and Meiqin Liu International Conference on Smart Computing and Communication (SmartCom), Springer, 2018.